Gould, William B., IV,NLRB Papers 6391
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
William B. Gould IV NLRB Papers
2004-2001
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Gould, William B., IV
National Labor Relations Board (NLRB)
6391
9 cubic feet
8 linear ft.
Articles, reports, pamphlets, correspondence, photographs, transcripts, news clippings, records.
The collection consists of correspondence, Congressional hearing files, and some case files from William B. Gould IV's tenure as the chairman of the NLRB.
8640380
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 08, 2015
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, May 08, 2015
Scope and Contents
Most of this collection dates from Gould's confirmation as Chairman of the NLRB in 1994 to his resignation in 1998. The collection includes material relating to his confirmation hearing. There are the official Congressional documents as well as documents, news clippings, and letters both opposing and supporting his confirmation. Also included are the NLRB Executive Chronological File, 1994-1998, correspondence with members of Congress, NLRB memoranda, NLRB press releases, and Gould's NLRB Diary. Congressional hearing files and NLRB case files make up a substantial part of the collection. Also significant are the speeches he gave as the Chairman of the NLRB.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Gould IV, William B.; U.S. House of Representatives Subcommittee on Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, and Related Agencies; National Labor Relations Board (NLRB)
8640380
- William B. Gould Confirmation Hearing, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters of Congratulations on Nominations and Gould's Replies, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Nomination - Schedule and Briefing Books, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Gould's Answers to Senator's Questions, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Excerpts from "Agenda for Reform", 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Gould Arbitration Decisions (Charles E. Buffon), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Nomination Material (folder 1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Nomination Material (folder 2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous Nomination Material (folder 3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Letters of Support for Gould's Nomination to the NLRR (folder 1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Letters of Support for Gould's Nomination to the NLRR (folder 2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Letters of Support for Gould's Nomination to the NLRR (folder 3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Opposition to Gould (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Confirmation (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Gould Confirmation Statements (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Congratulation Letters on Confirmation, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Executive Chron. File, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Scope and Contents
  March-December 1994
- Executive Chron. File, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  January-December 1995
- Executive Chron. File, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  January-June 1996
- Executive Chron. File, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  July-December 1996
- Executive Chron. File, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  January-March 1997
- Executive Chron. File, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  April-August 1997
- Executive Chron. File, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Septembe-December 1997
- Executive Chron. File, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  January-May 1998
- Executive Chron. File, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  June-August 1998
- Congressional Correspondence, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Congressional Correspondence, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Congressional Correspondence, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Congressional Correspondence, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Letters to White House Chief of Staff, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- NLRB Memoranda (Box 2, Folder 9)
- NLRB Memoranda, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- NLRB Memoranda, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- NLRB Memoranda, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- NLRB Memoranda, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- NLRB Special Distribution Memorandum, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  SD94-1 through SD94-16; includes index.
- NLRB Special Distribution Memorandum (Box 2, Folder 15)
  SD94-17 through SD94-30
- NLRB Special Distribution Memorandum, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  SD95-1 through SD95-11; includes index
- NLRB Special Distribution Memorandum, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  SD95-12 through SD95-28
- NLRB Press Releases, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- NLRB Press Releases, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- NLRB Press Releases, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- NLRB Press Releases, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  March-May 1997
- NLRB Press Releases, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  June-November 1997
- NLRB Press Releases, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- NLRB Diary of William B. Gould IV (Box 3, Folder 5)
- NLRB Diary of William B. Gould IV, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- NLRB Diary of William B. Gould IV, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- NLRB Review Binder Sections 1-10 with Index (Box 3, Folder 8)
- NLRB Review Binder Sections 11-15 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- NLRB Review Binder Sections 16-25 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- NLRB Review Binder Sections 26-34 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Appropriations Bill, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Appropriations Bills, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Effects of Fiscal Year, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Appropriations Bill, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Fiscal Year 1999 Requests, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- NLRB Funding Since 1994 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Board Statistics and Administrative Material (Box 3, Folder 18)
- John Canon: NLRB Voting Accord Study, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Handwritten Narrative by William B. Gould IV (Box 3, Folder 20)
  1 of 4 items labeled "Copies to go in box for meeting"
- US House of Representatives Committee on Small Business, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- US House of Representatives Committee on the Judiciary (, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- US House of Representatives on Economic and Educational Opportunities, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- 102-01 (A) Congressional Oversights Committee Personnel, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  March 4, 1996
- 102-01(A) Congressman Jay Dickey's Visit to the Board, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  June 6, 1996
- 102-01(A) Congressional Oversight Committee Inspector General Position, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  June 25, 1996
- 102-01(A) Congressional Committee Background Investigation Reports, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  July 8, 1996
- 102-01(A) Congressional Oversight Committee Travel of the Board, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  August 14, 1996
- 102-01(A) Congressional Oversight Committee Perdue Farms, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- 102-01(A) Congressional Oversight Committee Lundy Packing, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  August 21, 1996
- 102-01(A) Congressman John Conyers Meeting, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  August 22, 1996
- 102-01(A) Congressional Oversight Committee on Labor and Human Resources, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  September 12, 1996
- 102-01(A) Congressional Oversight Committee on Labor and Human Resources, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  September 17, 1996
- 102-01(A) Congressional Inquiry: Recess Appointments and Temporary and Contingency Workers, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  December 13, 996
- 102-01(A) Congressional Inquiry on EBEW and BLE Election, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  January 2, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressional Inquiry Postcards in Response to HCF Decision, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  January 9, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressional Inquiry on Effects of NLRA Implementation on Small Businesses, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  February 4, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressional Inquiry, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  March 4, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressional Inquiry Detroit News, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  March 11, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressional Hearing Questions on 1998 Appropriations, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  March 19, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressional Inquiry Application Files with NLB, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  April 22, 1997
- Congressional Inquiry Official Time, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  April 29, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressional Inquiry Final Rules, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  April 30, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressional Letter Inspector General Investigation, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  July 17, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressional Oversight Hearing, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  July 24, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressional Oversight Hearing: Mission, Management and Performance of the NLRB, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Congressional Oversight Hearing: Salting, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- 102-01(A) Congressional Oversight Hearing: 10(j), 1997 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- 102-01(A) Congressional Oversight Hearing: Gould's Statement, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- 102-01(A) Oversight of the NLRB Hearing, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- 102-01(A) Congressional Oversight Hearing, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  July 25, 1997
- 102.01(A) Congressional Oversight Committee: Travel and Sporting Events, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- 102-01(A) Congressman Bernard Sanders Request, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  August 7, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressional Inquiry: Sanders, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- 102-01(A) Tom Lantos Request, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  August 26, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressman Hoekstra and Fawell Letter, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  September 10, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressional Oversight Hearing: Donald Payne, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  September 27, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressional Inquiry: Joseph Jablonski, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  Decemberr 3, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressional Inquiry, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  December 12, 1997
- 102-01(A) Congressional Inquiry, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  February 24, 1998
- 102-01(A) Congressional Inquiry: Inspector General, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  March 20, 1998
- 102-01(A) Congressional Inquiry: NLRB El Paso, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  April 30, 1998
- 102-01(A) Congressional Inquiry: Sanders, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  June 23, 1998
- 102-01(A) NLRB Inspector General Offices, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- "Salting" Cases, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Statement Response: the Subcommittee on Labor, Health, and Human Services, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Gould's Response to Senator Don Nickles, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Gould's Statement to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Gould Statements to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the US Senate, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Gould Jurisdictional Threshold Statements, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Statement of "Gould" Board Case Work, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Reply to Letters of March 4, 1997 from Hawthorne, et. Al. (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Gould's Response to Oversight Committee, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Transcript and Questions for the Record from House Appropriations, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Congressional Record, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  June-Sept. 1995)
- Congressional Record, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  July 1996)
- Congressional Record, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  April 1997)
- Congressional Record, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Sept. 1997)
- Congressional Record, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Aug. 1998)
- OIG-I-173, OIG-I-187 Dynatech (folder 1 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- OGI-I-173, OIG-I-187 Dynatech (folder 2 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- OIG-I-173, OIG-I-187 Dynatech (folder 3 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- OIG-I-173, OIG-I-187 Dynatech (folder 4 of 4) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- OIG-I-229: OIG Report (Box 5, Folder 7)
  May 6, 1998.
- Correspondence Regarding the NLRB Inspector General 1998 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- NLRB Four and One-Half Year Report (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Decisions of the NLRB, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Decisions of the NLRB, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Decisions of the NLRB, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Board Practice Regarding Issuance of Decisions, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Decisions of the NLRB, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Board Agendas (Box 5, Folder 15)
- NLRB Procedures in Recess, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- NLRB Case No. 25-CA-19818, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- NLRB Case No. 2-CA-28177: Major League Baseball, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- NLRB Case No. 18-CA-13394: Overnight Transportation (Box 5, Folder 19)
- NLRB Case No. 4-CE-106: Sheraton University City Hospital, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- NLRB Case No. 11-RC-6094: Perdue Farms, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- NLB Case No. 13-CA-33085: Lincoln Park, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- NLRB Case No. 20-CA-23314: Morgan's Holiday Market, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- NLRB Case No. 37-RD-302: Hale Rehabilitation and Nursing Center, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- NLB Case No. 2-CA-31537: Zano's Bake Shop, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- NLRB Case No. 9-CA-3028: Transport International Express, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- NLRB Case No. 11-RC-6254: Sandvick Rock Tools, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- NLRB Case No. 16-RD-1414, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- NLRB Case No. 21-RL-19951: San Diego Harbor Excursions, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 29)
- NRLB Case No. 28-RD-776, 785, 786: MGM Grand, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- NLRB Case No. 7-RC-21737: The Wellness Plan, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Fired Sprint Worker (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Bro-Tech Corp. v. NLRB, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Marquez v. Screen Actors Guild, NLRB case no.97-1056 (folder 1 of 2), 1998 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Marquez v. Screen Actors Guild, NLRB case no.97-1056 (folder 2 of 2), 1998 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Advisory Panel, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Ethics Issues (Box 5, Folder 37)
- NLRB Photos, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- NLRB Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 2)
- National Mediation Board Case Regarding the Railway Labor Act (Box 6, Folder 3)
- US Court of Appeals, 9th Circuit: Children of the Rosary, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- BNA Newsletters (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Bureau of National Affairs Dairy Labor Report (Box 6, Folder 6)
  March 1993-February 1994
- Daily Labor Report (Box 6, Folder 7)
- NLRB Watch (Box 6, Folder 8)
- 501-03 Speech File: Book One: Chairman Gould Speeches, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Fiscal Year 1994 Index
- 501-03 Speech File: "The National Labor Relations Board Today", 1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-1980, May 6, 1994. Delivered at the Fifteenth Constitutional Convention of the Metropolitan Detroit AFL-CIO, Detroit, MI
- 501-03 Speech File: "A Speech for the Law School Hooding Ceremony", 1994 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  NLRB Press Release no.R.1981, May 20, 1994. In Observance of the University of Maryland at Baltimore Graduation Ceremonies, University of Maryland School of Law, Baltimore, MD
- 501-03 Speech File: "This Generation's Reconciliation", 1994 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-1984, May 28, 1994. Distinguished Speaker Luncheon, National Academy of Arbitrators Forty-Seventh Annual Meeting, Minneapolis, MN
- 501-03 Speech File: "The Last Chairman of the National Labor Relations Board?: The Law and Politics of Labor Policy in the First 100 Days", 1994 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-1990, June 10, 1994. The Commonwealth Club of America Luncheon Meeting, San Francisco, CA
- 501-03 Speech File: "Status of the National Labor Relations Board", 1994 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-1992, June 14, 1994. Edward L. Cushman Memorial Symposium on Labor-Management Relations in the 21st Century, Detroit, MI
- 501-03 Speech File: "The NLRB's Deferral to Arbitration Policy", 1994 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-1993, June 15, 1994. American Arbitration Association's Upstate New York Disppute Resolution Day, Rochester, NY
- 501-03 Speech File: "Changes in Labor Law: Here and Now and the Future", 1994 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2005, August 22, 1994. Washington State Labor Council Constitutional Convention, Spokana, WA
- 501-03 Speech File: "Building the Labor-Management Partnership: The Role of the National Labor Relations Board", 1994 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2011, September 12, 1994. The Employers Group Dinner Meeting, Los Angeles, CA
- 501-03 Speech file: "Overview of Labor Law in the United States", 1994 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2016, September 19, 1994. U.S.-Mexico Conference on Labor Law and industrial Relations, Washington, D.C.
- 501-03 Speech File: "Statement Before the Commission on the Future of Worker-Management Relations", 1994 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2019, September 29, 1994. Washington, D.C.
- 501-03 Speech File: "Labor Law and Policy in the '90s: The Role of the National Labor Relations Board", 1994 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2022, October 3, 1994. Ninth Annual Rhode Island Conference on Labor-Management Relations, Providence, RI
- 501-03 Speech File: "Recent Developments Before the National Labor Relations Board: The Role of Conciliatioon and Other Dispute Resolution Mechanisms", 1994 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2028, December 9, 1994. State Bar of Georgia/Atlanta Bar Association: Labor and Employment Law Sections' Labor and Employment Law Institute, Atlanta, GA
- 501-03 Speech File: "Labor Law Reform in the U.S. and Europe", 1994 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2029, December 13, 1994. IESS/EPI International Conference on New Organization of Work and New Industrial Relations, Rome, Italy
- 501-03 Speech File: "Statement in Response to Dunlop Commission Report", 1994 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2035, January 9, 1995. Washington, D.C.
- 501-03 Speech File: "The Right to Strike in a Democratic Society", 1995 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2041, February 24, 1995. Remarks Before the Bar Association of San Francisco, Labor and Employment Section, San Francisco, CA
- 501-03 Speech File: "The Curse of the Bambino", 1995 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2065, April 27, 1995. Baseball and the "Sultan of Swat" A Conference Commemorating the 100th Birthday of Babe Ruth, Hempstead, NY
- 501-03 Speech File: "NLRB Chairman Gould Urges Law School Grads to Consider Public Service Careers", 1995 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2069, May 14, 1995. Columbus, OH
- 501-03 Speech File: Book Two: Chairman Gould Speeches, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  Fiscal Year 1995 Index
- 501-03 Speech File: "The NLRB at the Crossroads: NLRB Sixtieth Anniversary, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2074, May 18, 1995. American Bar Association Section of Labor and Employment Law 60th Anniversary Celebration of the National Labor Relations Act, Washington, D.C.
- 501-03 Speech File: "Serving the Public Interest Through the Rule of Law: A Trilogy of Values", 1995 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  May 21, 1995. In Observance of the District of Columbia School of Law Graduation Ceremony, Washington, D.C.
- 501-03 Speech File: "Cooperation or Conflict: Problems and Potential in the National Labor Relations Act", 1995 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2077, May 31, 1995New York University's 48th National Conference on Labor, New York, NY
- 501-03 Speech File: "New Procedures Under the National Labor Relations Act: Some Challenges for the Labor Board", 1995 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2078, June 9, 1995. 28th Annual Pacific Coast Labor Law Conference, Seattle, WA
- 501-03 Speech File: "Professional Sports, Collective Bargaining and the Law", 1995 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2085, June 27, 1995. Sports Law National Conference, Minneapolis, MN
- 501-03 Speech File: Statement Before the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  July 12, 1995. Washington, D.C.
- 501-03 Speech File: Statement Regarding Proposed Budget Cut, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2087, July 20, 1995. Washington, D.C.
- 501-03 Speech File: "In Memory of Walter Philip Reuther", 1995 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2099, September 8, 1995. Walter P. Reuther 25th Commemorative Tribute, Detroit, MI
- 501-03 Speech File: Book Three: Chairman Gould Speeches (Box 6, Folder 36)
  Fiscal Year 1996 - Index
- 501-03 Speech File: "The Perils and Progress of the National Labor Relations Board: An Enduring Legacy", 1995 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2114, October 5, 1995. Conference Sponsored by Cornell University School of Industrial and Labor Relations and the National Labor Relations Board on National Labor Policy at the 60th Anniversary of the NLRB and the Wagner Act, Wash
- 501-03 Speech File: "The National Labor Relations Board: The Undiscussed Decisions of Our Agency", 1995 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2116, October 9, 1995. National Labor Relations Board Region 1: U.S. Department of Labor Conference. Co-Sponsored by the Massachusetts Bar Association, the Boston Bar Association, the Federal Bar Association, Boston, MA
- 501-03 Speech File: "The Work of the Labor Board and the State of the Employment Relationship in America", 1995 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2118, November 3, 1995. The State University of New Jersey, Rutgers School of Management and Labor Relations, Fall State Advisor Council Meeting, New Brunswick, NJ
- 501-03 Speech File: "A Tale of Three Agencies: The NLRB Experience", 1996 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  January 5, 1996. Industrial Relations Research Association's 48th Annual Meeting, Distinguished Panel Discussion Consisting of: William B. Gould IV, National Labor Relations Board; Magdalena (Maggie) Jacobson, National Mediation Board; John Calhoun Wells
- 501-03 Speech File: "In Honor of the 100th Anniversary of the San Francisco Building Trades Council", 1996 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2123, February 2, 1996. San Francisco, CA
- 501-03 Speech File: Statement Before the Subcommittee on Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, and Related Agencies of the Senate Committee on Appropriations, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  February 6, 1996. Washington, D.C.
- 501-03 Speech File: "Current Directions of Labor Law in the United States: Some Comparative Reflections", 1996 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2125, February 20, 1996. In Honor of the 50th Anniversary of the Creation of the Japan Labor Relations Commission (JLRC), Tokyo, Japan
- 501-03 Speech File: "Beyond 'Them an Us' Litigation: The Clinton Board's Administrative Reforms and Decisions Promoting Labor-Management Cooperation", 1996 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2127, February 29, 1996. National Labor Relations Board Region Twenty-Five and Indiana University School of Law Indianapolis Seventeenth Annual Seminar on Labor-Management Relations, Indianapolis, IN
- 501-03 Speech File: "Statement by William B. Gould IV on the Occasion of his Second Anniversary as Chairman of the National Labor Relations Board", 1996 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  March, 7, 1996. Washington, D.C.
- 501-03 Speech File: "NLRB Chairman Gould Says Proposed Single Unit Rule Would Codify Existing Law, Speed Up Case Processing, and Cut Costs", 1996 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2129, March 7, 1996. Washington, D.C.
- 501-03 Speech File: Statement Before the Subcommittee on Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, and Related Agencies of the House Committee on Appropriations, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  March 14, 1996. Washington, D.C.
- 501-03 Speech File: "NAFTA, American Labor Law and the Idea of International Labor Standards", 1996 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2131, March 18, 1996. Cooperative Work Program of the North American Agreement on Labor Cooperation (NAALC), Canada-United States-Mexico Tripartite Conference on "Industrial Relations for the 21st Century", Montreal, Canada
- 501-03 Speech File: "Baseball Should Not Tinker With the Game Itself", 1996 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2133, April 2, 1996. Washington, D.C.
- 501-03 Speech File: "In the Wake of the Blizzard of '96 and the Government Shutdowns: Part II of the Clinton Board's Decisions", 1996 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  NLRB Press Release no.R-2134, April 19, 1996. Case Western Reserve University Public Policy Forum, Cleveland, OH
- 501-03 Speech File: Statement o Auciello Iron Works, Inc. v. NLRB, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 51)